Welcome to our training on how to earn a brand referral bonus.
Are you a brand owner selling in the U.
S.
Amazon Store?
With the brand referral bonus program, you can earn a bonus averaging 10% of product sales driven
by your non-Amazon marketing efforts.
That means the more traffic you drive to your Amazon listings, the more opportunities you have to
earn a bonus.
Today we'll cover how this program works, as well as the two-part process to enroll.
When you direct traffic to your Amazon listings from your non-Amazon marketing, you can earn an
average 10% bonus from qualifying sales.
The exact bonus percentage varies by product category and is provided as a credit on your seller
referral fees.
You'll also earn the same bonus if a customer purchases additional products from your brand up to
two weeks after clicking your ad.
All brand owners selling in Amazon's U.
S.
Store are eligible to enroll, and you can get started by following this two-part process.
First, you'll need to enroll in the brand referral bonus program.
To do this, sign in to Seller Central.
From the pop-out menu, hover over Brands and select Brand Referral Bonus.
On the Brand Referral Bonus page, you can enroll with one click if your brand is eligible.
Once enrolled, you'll be prompted to fill out the tax form required to receive your bonus.
Once you've enrolled in the program, you're ready to create tags for your campaigns with Amazon
attribution.
Amazon attribution is a free tool that measures how your non-Amazon digital marketing impacts your
sales activity in the Amazon Store.
To earn your bonus, all of your off Amazon marketing must have an Amazon attribution tag applied
to it.
To create and generate your tags, access Amazon attribution directly on the Brand Referral Bonus
page, or through your Amazon Advertising Console account.
On the Amazon attribution dashboard, select Create Campaign.
On the new Amazon attribution campaign page, you'll see two options for creating a campaign.
Select the bulk upload method for Google Search and Facebook campaigns to easily tag and measure
Google Search keywords or Facebook ads by uploading a single file.
Or select Create Manually, where you'll be prompted to set up campaign structure and provide campaign
details to generate tags.
Next, provide a name for your campaign and select the products you'll be promoting as well as any
associated variations.
Once you've selected your products, you'll create an ad group for each of your off Amazon marketing
strategies.
For each group, enter a name based on the strategy or tactic for the relevant tag.
Next, select the Publisher and Channel corresponding to the campaign you're measuring.
Then, provide the click-through URL to your Amazon Store or Product Detail page you'll drive customers
to when they click your ad.
Once complete, select Create to generate an attribution tag for each ad group shown in the attribution
tag column.
You can download all tags in a file or copy each tag individually.
Finally, implement these tags in your off Amazon campaigns.
To do this, copy and paste the tags into the corresponding destination URL field within your non-
Amazon campaign.
For example, if you're running an ad on social media, visit the ad manager within that platform.
You'll then copy and paste each tag into the destination URL field.
Each Publisher system is different, so this process may vary slightly.
As your campaigns drive sales, you'll begin earning your bonus, which is provided as a credit towards
your seller referral fees.
The bonus applies to brand-owned products with an Amazon attribution tag and customer purchase resulting
from a non-Amazon marketing effort.
Bonuses vary by product category and are subject to a two-month wait to accommodate any cancellations
and returns.
You can download your weekly bonus report on the brand referral bonus page in Seller Central.
This report is updated every Friday with your estimated bonus amount earned up to the previous week.
For more information on this program, search for brand referral bonus in Seller Central.
For more information on Amazon attribution, review the Help Center content within the Amazon Advertising
Console.
This concludes our training on how to earn a brand referral bonus.
You now have the tools to drive traffic to your Amazon listings and start earning your bonus.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store!